A Finding Aid to the Allyn Cox Papers, 1856-1982 AAA.coxally
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1878-1982; Series 2; 6.74 Linear feet Boxes 1-7, 12, OV 13
  - General Correspondence, 1916-1982; 2.2
    - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - G, General, circa 1934-1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hancock, Walker, 1950s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Harbeson, John F., circa 1954-circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Harison & Hewitt, 1967-1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Harsch, Anne and Joseph C., circa 1944-circa 1982 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    - Henderson, Jack, circa 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Hendrickson, David, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Hessler, Gene, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Hobbs, Susan, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Holland Lodge, 1950s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Honeycutt, Ann, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Howland, Richard (Dick), circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Hoyt, Austin and Maggy, 1967-1977 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - H, General, circa 1916-1981 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Interchemical Corporation, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - I, General, 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Jayme, William North, 1950s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Jofa, Inc., 1946-1956 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Jorgensen, Julia Dorothea, 1940s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
    - J, General, 1940s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Keally, Francis, circa 1940s-1967 (Box 4, Folder 42-43)
    - Kenyon, W. Houston, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Knowlton, Evelyn, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - K, General, 1940s-1980 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Landau, Sarah B., 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Laning, Edward, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Lay, Charles Downing, circa 1950s (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Lemon, Janet, 1960-1976 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Linder, Raymond J., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Lindsay, John V., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Little, Nina and Betram, 1946-1971 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Lothrop, Eleanor, 1970s-1981 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - L, General, 1919-1981 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Mark Twain Memorial, Hartford, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Markel, F. H., circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
    - Martin, Jay, 1964-1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - McIlvaine, Diana, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Melcher, Betsy, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Mendel, Mesick, Cohen, Architects, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1940s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Molinari, Everett, 1970s-1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Municipal Art Society, 1940s-1960s (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Murray, Richard N., 1970s (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - M, General, circa 1930-1982 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - National Academy of Design, 1940-1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - National City Bank, 1954-1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - National Society Daughters of the American Revolution, 1956-1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - National Society of Mural Painters, circa 1936-1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - New York Society Library, 1957-1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - New York World's Fair Horticultural Exposition Building, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Norfolk Naval Hospital, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - N, General, 1941-1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Old Sturbridge Village, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - O, General, 1949-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Page, Thornton, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Pilgrimage to Mecca" Mural, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Pirie, Robert, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Poor, Albert Easton, 1948-1969 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Potter, Clarkson N., circa 1956-1982 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Potter, Harriet, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Potter, Maggie (Mrs. J.H.N.), circa 1960s-1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Pulsifer, Nathaniel, circa 1950s-1982 (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
    - Purves, Austin Jr., 1950-1958 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - P, General, 1930-1982 (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
    - Queens College, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Quinn, Henrietta, circa 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Q, General, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Reed, Henry Hope, Jr., 1950s-1982 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Richardson, Elisa, circa 1921-circa 1926 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Ross, Sally Price and Howard, circa 1970s-circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Royal Arch Masons (Ray and William Denslow), 1959-1967 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Russell, Richard, 1955-1974 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - R, General, 1920-1982 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
    - S. S. America Dining Saloon, 1939-1946 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Saarinen, Aline B., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Saint-Gaudens Museum/National Historic Site, 1947-1982 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Saint Paul's Hospital, Dallas, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
    - Salter, Katharine Hayden, 1961-1977 (Box 5, Folder 52-53)
    - Schmidt, Elena and Mott, 1951-1980 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Schoenfeld, R. E., 1973-1979 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Scholz, Helen, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - School Art League of New York City, 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Secrest, Meryle Beveridge, circa 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Seymour, Whitney North Jr., circa 1966-1977 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Sherman, Marjorie, circa 1972 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Shipman, Jr., Mary and Arthur, circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Shurcliff Family, 1934-1981 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Shutze, Philip Trammell, circa 1950s-circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 63-65)
    - Shutze, Philip Trammell, circa 1950s-circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
      Folder 5 includes lillustrated letter from Shutze
    - Skogstad, Agnes, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Henry Clapp, circa 1950s (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Smith, Katharine Dennis, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Smithsonian Institution, Cooper-Hewit Museum, 1950-1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Smithsonian Institution, Museum of History and Technology, 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 10-13)
    - Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Arts, 1957-1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Smithsonian Institution, National Portrait Gallery, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Spackman, Emily and Flogel, 1942-1947 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - State University of New York at Binghamton, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Steese, Edward (Ned), 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Stout, George L., 1941-1963 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Sturges, William Knight, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Supreme Council, Freemasons, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - S, General, circa 1940s-1981 (Box 6, Folder 22-24)
    - Tennessee State Capitol, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Theodore H. Smith & Co., Inc., 1962-1974 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Treadwell, Helen, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - T, General, 1934-1982 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Unitarian Church of Hampton Falls, New Hampshire, 1950-1952 (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
    - United States Capitol
      - Completion of Rotunda Frieze, 1950-1954 (Box 6, Folder 31-34)
      - Completion of Rotunda Frieze, Reports, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 35-37)
      - Completion of Rotunda Frieze, Reports and Photos, 1950s (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Congressional Reports and Resolutions, 1925-1982 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Contracts, 1971-1981 (Box 6, Folder 40-41)
      - Cox Corridor Murals, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 42-44)
      - Cox Corridor Murals, 1969-1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Financial Records, 1970-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Fresco Contracts, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - General Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
      - Plans and Sketches (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Restoration of Dome Canopy, 1956-1960 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
      - Senate Reception Room, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
    - United States Congress Members, 1973-1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - University Club, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - University of California, 1954-1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - University of Georgia, Georgia Museum of Art, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - University of Virginia Clark Hall Murals, 1939; 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - U, General, 1940-1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - V, General, 1916-1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Walker, John (National Gallery of Art), 1968-1973 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Warner, Sturge and Hilda, circa 1970s-1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Weems, K., circa 1960s-1981 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Wellons, Michael E., 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - White, Larry Grant, 1940s (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Wilkinson, Burke, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - William B. May Co., Inc., 1974-1981 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Writings and Notes, 1919-1982; Series 3; 0.58 Linear feet Boxes 7-8
        Series includes Cox's handwritten manuscripts, typescripts, and notes for several lectures in addition to a collection of index note cards and loose notes on art-related subjects, individual projects, and research sources. The cards also include contact information for people and art-related resources.
        Also found is a diary belonging to Ethel Cox, which includes reference to Cox's work on the Moses panel for the University of Virginia, as well as a 1955 diary excerpt in which Ethel Cox recounts a period of illness that Allyn Cox endured in May-June, 1955.
        - Column, "An American Student in Paris," for Columbia University, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 36)
        - "Eugene Francis Savage", circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 37)
        - Lecture for Bowdoin College, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 38)
        - Lecture, "Castle Hill Lecture", 1955 (Box 7, Folder 39)
        - Lecture, "Color and Light in Painting by Roland Rood", circa 1946 (Box 7, Folder 40)
        - Lecture on Composition and Color, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 41)
        - Lecture on Mural Painting, circa 1960s (Box 7, Folder 42)
        - Lecture, "Wall Paintings in the Alsop House", circa 1951 (Box 7, Folder 43)
        - Lists and Notes, circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 44)
        - Note Cards, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 7, Folder 45-50)
        - Notebook, Rome Frescoes, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 51)
        - Notes, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 52-53)
        - Notes, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
        - Notes for Lecture "The Practice of Mural Painting", 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - Notes on Technical Information and Materials, circa 1925-circa 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        - Unidentified Typescript, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - Diary of Ethel Cox, 1923-1936 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - Diary of Ethel Cox, Excerpt, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Wright, John, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - W, General, 1941-1982 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Young, Cliff and Ann, circa 1970s-1982 (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
    - Y, General, 1927-1982 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Z, General, circ1 1960s (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - First Names Only, A-G, circa 1940s-circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - First Names Only, H-L, circa 1940-circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - First Names Only, M-W, circa 1940-circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Illegible and Unidentified, circa 1921-circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Oversized George Washington Masonic National Memorial from Box 4, Folders 1-11 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Oversized American Battle Monuments Comission from Box 2, Folder 25 (Box OV 13)
    - Oversized Emma Romeyn Inc from Box 3, Folder 44 (Box OV 13)
    - Oversized United States Capitol, Plans and Sketches from Box 7, Folder 7 (Box OV 13)
- Research Files, circa 1950s-circa 1970s; Series 4; 0.25 Linear feet Boxes 8, 12
  Research files contain source material used by Cox on various subjects including photos and printed material documenting the history and architecture of the United States Capitol and other state capitols, clippings related to artist models, and news articles on miscellaneous subjects.
  - Architecture, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Capitol Buildings, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 12-16)
    Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 3
  - Models, circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous from Box 8, Folders 12-16 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Printed Material, 1920s-1982; Series 5; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 8-9
  Announcements and catalogs are primarily for Allyn Cox and include exhibitions in which he was featured as well as dedications and unveilings of his murals. Also found are copies of articles written by Cox, and news articles documenting his career, and other subjects including a folder of articles about Kenyon Cox; blank postcards; and brochures, pamphlets, and newsletters of organizations related to Cox's work and interests.
  Also found is a copy of a master's thesis on Kenyon Cox by Betty Jo Carroll.
  - Announcements and Catalogs, Cox, circa 1930s-1982 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Articles About Cox, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Articles About Cox, 1920s-1982 (Box 8, Folder 21-28)
  - Articles by Cox, 1950, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Articles About Kenyon Cox, circa 1903-circa 1919 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Articles and Newsclippings, General, circa 1920s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 31-32)
  - Blank Postcards, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets and Newletters, circa 1950s-1982 (Box 8, Folder 34-35)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets and Newletters, United States Capitol, 1950s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Master's Thesis by Betty Jo Carroll: "Kenyon Cox: Proponent of Academia in American Art During the Advent of Modernism", 1978 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Newsletters of Essex County Greenbelt Association, 1975-1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters of Royal Arch Masons, 1950s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Sketchbooks and Sketches, 1873-circa 1978; Series 6; 0.25 Linear feet Box 9, OVs 13-14
  Series includes 4 of Cox's sketchbooks and circa 22 loose sketches. Sketches are primarily figure, animal, architectural, and landscape sketches in pencil, charcoal, and ink.
  Also found are two circa 1943 sketches entered into a War Department mural competition: one of tempera and gouache on board, drawn to a ratio of 1":1', and marked "120A"; the other a full-sized detail, in the same media, and marked "120B."
  Also found is an 1873 sketchbook by Kenyon Cox of people and scenes in Ohio.
  - Entry for War Department Mural Competion, circa 1943 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Oversized material housed in OVs 13-14
  - Skechbook, circa 1910 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbooks, circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - Loose Sketches, circa 1918-circa 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Kenyon Cox Sketchbook, 1873 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Entry for War Department Mural Competition from Box 9, Folder 3 (Box OVs 13-14)
- Photographs, 1856-circa 1980; Series 7; 2.25 Linear feet Boxes 9-12, OV 13
  Photographs are of Cox from childhood to the 1980s; his family including parents, siblings, and grandparents; friends including Philip Trammell Shutze and Warner Bishop; family residences; artist models; events; and artwork, including many of Cox's commissions.
  Series includes vintage photographic media including: 2 tintypes of Cox and his siblings at Grant's tomb; 2 tintypes of Leonard Cox; an ambrotype of Anna Stott King, Louise Cox's mother; photos, including a cyanotype and a tintype of Louise Cox; a cyanotype, of Cox's grandmother Helen Finney Cox; photos of Cox's grandfathers, General Jacob Dolson Cox, and Reverend Charles G. Finney; and a circa 1910 platinum print, probably of Ethel Cox, by the Misses Selby.
  Vintage photos of Kenyon Cox include 3 tintypes; 2 carte de visites in the studio of George Becker; a silver gelatin print by Pirie Macdonald, circa 1905; a period reproduction of a portrait, circa 1885; and a photo of an engraved portrait, circa 1895. Additional photos of Louise and Kenyon Cox include a series of circa 1906 photographs taken in a garden with their children and other unidentified people.
  Photos of Allyn Cox and family include portraits and photos of Cox with Ethel Cox. Photographs of Cox working include two 1920 photo postcards of him at work on an unidentified mural in Rome, and photos of him working in the United States Capitol. Also found are photos by John Barrington Bayley taken inside an unidentified church; and various black and white and color snapshots. Several photos of Cox with members of Congress include one with President Gerald Ford.
  Photos of houses and residences include snapshots of Villa La Cappilla and Villa Malatesta labeled as "mother's house in Honolulu," a group labeled "Essex, Massachusetts," and another group labeled "Essex and N.Y. houses." Also found are photos of other residences in Italy, and several postcards of the Cox residence in Cornish, New Hampshire.
  Many of Cox's commissions are documented in photographs of artwork, including Dumbarton Oaks, interiors of many private residences, the George Washington Masonic National Memorial Association Temple, the interior of the Lido Venice restaurant in New York shown in a series of 1926 photographs by Kenneth Clark, the United States Capitol, the William A. Clarke Memorial Library, and several photos which originally formed part of a dismantled scrapbook. Scattered photos of Cox at work can also be found with these photos. Formats include photographic prints, slides, and negatives. 10 glass plate negatives of artwork by Cox are housed separately and are closed to researchers.
  - Of Cox, Art Students League Class, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Of Cox, Childhood, circa 1897-circa 1910 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Of Cox, Events, 1950s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Of Cox, Family, 1927-1946 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Of Cox, Family and Friends, circa 1890s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 14-16)
  - Of Cox's Grandparents, circa 1864-circa 1880s (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - Of Cox, Members of U. S. Congress, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Of Cox, Portraits, 1931-circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Of Cox, Working, 1920s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 21-23)
  - Of Cox, Ethel and Family, circa 1902-circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Oversized photograph, possibly of Ethel Cox by the Misses Selby, housed in Box 12, Folder 4
  - Of Cox, Kenyon, circa 1880s-circa 1905 (Box 9, Folder 25-28)
    Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 5
  - Of Cox, Kenyon, Art Students League Class, circa 1887 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Of Cox, Kenyon, Family and Friends, circa 1906 (Box 9, Folder 30-32)
  - Of Cox, Leonard, circa 1900-circa 1920 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Of Cox, Louise, circa 1860s-circa 1930s (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
  - Of King, Anna Stott, circa 1960s-circa 1890s (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Of Lansing, Caroline Cox, circa 1900-circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Of Bishop, Warner, circa 1930s (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Of Shutze, Philip Trammell and Projects, 1920-circa 1940s (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Of Houses and Residences, 1856-circa 1960 (Box 9, Folder 40-44)
  - Of Launch of "Ronald and Mary Jane" by Walker Hancock, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Of Models, circa 1930s-circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 46-48)
  - Of Models, circa 1930s-circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Of U. S. Capitol, Corridor from Statuary Hall by C. Young, ca 1960s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Of Artwork by Cox
    - Altarpieces, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - American Legion Building, Paris, France, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Calhoun House, Atlanta, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Candleabra, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Chapel of Norfolk Naval Hospital, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Cosmopolitan Club, New York, NY, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Drawings, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Dumbarton Oaks, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Finished Cartoons, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 13-16)
    - Floyd Bennett Field Mess Hall, circa 1942 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - George Washington Masonic National Memorial Association Temple, circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
    - Guaranty Trust Co., New York, "West Point" Mural, circa 1946 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Home in Atlanta, Murals, circa 1931 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Home in Chicago, Murals, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Home Interiors, Miscellaneous, circa 1920s-circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Home of E. J. Stehli, circa 1921 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Home of John Innes Kane, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Home of Murphys, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 26)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 6
    - Home of Spackmans, New York, NY, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Home of Vincent Astor, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Home of William Alsop, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Hospital in Dallas, TX, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Interchemical Corporation, circa 1943 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Lido Venice Restaurant, New York, NY, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 7
    - Lord and Taylor, New York, NY, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Military Cemetery, Hamm, Luxembourg, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Mosaics, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Murals, Unidentified, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 36-39)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 6 and OV 13
    - Naval Hospital, Portsmouth, VA, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - National City Company, circa 1928 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Paintings, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 42-43)
    - Portraits, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Rome Chimneypiece Panel, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 45)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 8
    - S. S. America, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Smithsonian Institution Museum of History and Technology, circa 1958-circa 1960 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Stained Glass Windows, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Studies, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Unitarian Church of Hampton Falls, circa 1952 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - United States Capitol, circa 1950s-circa 1980s (Box 10, Folder 51-57)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12 Folder 8
    - University of Virginia Law School, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - University Seals, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - William A. Clarke Memorial Library, UCLA, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Contents of a Scrapbook, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Color Transparencies, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Slide File 1, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
    - Slide File 2, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
    - Negatives and Slides, Unsorted, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Slide Viewer, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 10 glass plate negatives (Box MGP3)
  - Of Artwork by Kenyon Cox, circa 1903 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Oversized Photos of Cox, Ethel and Family from Box 9, Folder 24 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Photos of Cox, Kenyon from Box 9, Folders 25-28 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Cox, Home of Murphys from Box 10, Folders 26 and 36-39 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Cox from Box 10, Folder 32 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Cox from Box 10, Folders 45, 51-57, 58, 60 and Box 11, Folder 1 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Photos of Artwork by Cox, Murals, Unidentified from Box 10, Folder 36-39 (Box OV 13)